npd.com 2016-11-16

# Privacy Policy

**Privacy Statement:**   
As specialists in consumer research, we at The NPD Group know how important your privacy is, and we are committed to making protection of your privacy a top priority. This statement outlines our online privacy policy for our corporate Web site, npd.com, and related sites. To make this notice easy to find, we make it available on our homepage and at every point where personally-identifiable information may be requested. In addition, as a member of the Council of American Survey Research Organizations (CASRO), the professional trade association of survey research companies, The NPD Group adheres to the mandated CASRO Code of Standards and Ethics for Survey Research. You may visit CASRO, and view the CASRO Code, at [www.casro.org](http://www.casro.org/).

**Information Collected On Our Site:**   
In several areas of the Web site, The NPD Group gives you the option of providing personal data in order to receive more detailed information on our products or services, to be added to one of our mailing lists, or to order a specific study or report.   
The personal information collected at these areas of our site includes:

Name   
Company Name   
Position   
Address   
Phone   
Email 

In addition, The NPD Group's Web server automatically recognizes some information about our visitors, including the company that provides their Internet service. Our server does not automatically recognize names, addresses, email addresses, or similar information specific to you as an individual.

**How We Use This Information:**   
When you submit personal information in order to receive NPD mailings or to order one of our reports, the information you submit is used only for that purpose. The NPD Group does not share your personal information with any other company or with individuals outside of our company.

Our server log, which records all transactions and the IP addresses that request them, is used to monitor traffic flow on our site in order to manage the site more effectively and to make sure its content is useful. Cookies may occasionally be used only to enhance your experience on our site and to make our site easier for you to navigate. To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

**Keeping Your Personal Information Accurate:**   
You can check the accuracy of any personal information The NPD Group has in our records, opt to be removed from any NPD mailing lists, or discontinue receipt of further marketing or press communications from NPD at any time by [emailing us](mailto:feedback@npd.com) or contacting us by mail or phone at: 

The NPD Group   
900 West Shore Road   
Port Washington, NY 11050   
(516) 625-0700

**Security:**   
Your safety is important to us, and we're committed to helping you safeguard your personal information on the Internet. Scammers may impersonate legitimate businesses such as The NPD Group by sending email or directing you to a Web site that appears to be from us but is not, a process known as "phishing." To learn more about phishing and other online scams, please visit [On Guard Online](http://www.onguardonline.gov/), a comprehensive U.S. government resource.

**The NPD Group will NOT do any of the things below:**

  * Ask you to provide us with financial information such as credit card/bank account numbers
  * Invite you to participate in a mystery shopping program
  * Have you cash a check and keep a portion of the proceeds

Throughout your Internet activities it's important to be on the lookout for fraud and to remember that if something seems too good to be true, it probably is. If you receive a suspicious email claiming to be from The NPD Group, please forward it to [spoof@npd.com](mailto:spoof@npd.com). We'll respond within 72 hours and let you know if it's a legitimate NPD e-mail.

To report fraud/phishing emails to the appropriate authorities, please forward them to [spam@uce.gov](mailto:spam@uce.gov) and/or [reportphishing@antiphishing.org. You can also file complaints with the ](mailto:reportphishing@antiphishing.org)[Federal Trade Commission](https://www.ftccomplaintassistant.gov/) and [Internet Crime Center](http://www.ic3.gov/default.aspx).

The NPD Group takes great pride in our stringent privacy policy, and we work closely with leading privacy and consumer protection organizations including the [Better Business Bureau](http://www.bbb.org/). To learn more, please read our full privacy policy.
